Teodor Fratiloiu

teodor.fratiloiu@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/teodor-fratiloiu | +44 20 3239 8947

UK HPI Visa Holder (right to work starting Jun 15), EU Citizen

Profile

Recent graduate of the Technical University of Munich with an MS degree in EE. Specialized in machine learning, embedded systems, high-performance computing and cybersecurity. During my studies, I gained 2 years of work experience in a hyper-growth environment (5x team-level, 3x company growth) at Celonis, Germany's and New York's highest-valued startup.

Education

Technical University of Munich (TUM) -

M.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology (2020-2023)

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology (2017-2020)

Work Experience

JUNIOR INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST, CELONIS; MUNICH (GERMANY) – DEC 2020 - FEB 2023

- Developed automations to collect over 50 types of evidence for continuous compliance with ISO 27001 and SOC 2, identified and harmonized audit control gaps across various frameworks
- Helped author and test BC/DR plans for EMEA and NA entities, conferred with stakeholders to account for critical data assets in 2 enterprise SaaS products hosted in a multi-cloud environment
- Periodically reviewed the access rights to cloud systems with up to 6-digit user counts; crossqueried databases to ensure appropriateness
- Assisted with writing security policies, SOPs, and training material, managed automated phishing training for the entire organization

STUDENT ASSISTANT, TUM - MAY 2020 - JAN 2021

Prepared lab content for students, explained solutions and hosted educational videos. Assisted the rest of the teaching staff during live remote classes for students in Munich and Singapore.

MEMBER AND MENTOR, ADVEISOR (TUM) - 2018 - 2019

Participated in a 1-year soft-skills and personal development program with professional coaching, including several 3-5 day offsite seminars in the Bavarian Alps. Applied the acquired knowledge by hosting over 10 project management and business communication workshops during my second year of university for "mentee" freshmen, which helped me find and perfect my own leadership style.

Technical Project Experience

MASTER'S THESIS - PEEKING INTO THE DECISION-MAKING PROCESS IN THE HUMAN MIND VIA DEEP LEARNING MODELS

- Collected and engineered labelled training data to represent >12,000 trading decisions (Pandas)
- Architected and trained deep learning models to emulate human decision-making (Keras, JAX)
- Assessed the performance of my own DL models against existing behavioral economics theories in a large-scale experiment

DISTRIBUTED, HIGH PERFORMANCE COMPUTING - LAB

- Solved a very large asynchronous value iteration problem using C++17 and multithreading
- Learned multiprocessing (OpenMP), MPI, CFFI, and created my own build systems in CMake

FULLY REMOTE API-BASED IOT PROGRAMMING - LAB

- Wrote complex TypeScript routines for a remote IoT "factory" with sensors and servo robots
- Deployed said scripts over the public Internet while observing the results via a live video feed

FUTURE ELECTRICITY PRICE PREDICTION - TEAM PROJECT

 Implemented a time-series prediction algorithm with reinforcement learning, developed our own full-stack web-app to visualize the results

BACHELOR'S THESIS - TINYFACE: EXTREME EDGE FACE DETECTION ON EMBEDDED DEVICES

 Trained, then compressed a neural network to function on low-power embedded hardware via pruning, graph analysis and quantization as part of a new research project (PhD level); returned to embedded ML during my master's by reengaging with the same group

ASTEROIDS ON AN STM32 MOBILE CONSOLE - LAB

- Programmed the Atari classic in C to have it run on microcontrollers with color displays and joysticks, including wired local multiplayer; enforced real-time constraints in the system
- Learned computer architecture, task scheduling and OS fundamentals, created embeddedspecific build systems and toolchains

Skills

Programming - C (including embedded), C++11 and up (incl. HPC), Python, JS/TS, TensorFlow/ Keras, Pandas, OpenCV, Docker & cloud, Git, UNIX

Security - ISO 27001, SOC 2, NIST, OWASP

Fully trilingual - English, German, Romanian